César Siguencia

Location: New York, NY 10031 Email: <u>cesar.siguencia@gmail.com</u> Phone: (646) 457-7006

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/cesar-siguencia
GitHub: github.com/cesarsiguencia

Portfolio: cesarsiguencia.github.io/my-react-portfolio

Full stack web developer with a strong background in education and passionate about developing productivity and social media apps. Team player with extensive experience in customer service and data management who prioritizes communication, career development, and organization at any workplace. Biggest strengths include time management, creativity, availability to others, and having a "whatever it takes" attitude towards challenges.

SKILLS

Front End: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Handlebars, JQuery, Bootstrap

Back End: Node, Express, Python, MySQL, MVC, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, APIs, RESTful, Graph QL, Bcrypt, PWA

Development Technologies: Git, GitHub, VSCode, CLI, Heroku, Insomnia, Apollo

Computer Skills: Microsoft Office Suite, Google Drive, Apple OSX, Windows, Logic Pro, Final Cut Pro, MailChimp General Skills: Multitasking, data and systems management, managing small teams, HR, public speaking, presentation experience, customer support experience, extensive verbal and writing skills, audio and video production, IT/hardware support

PROJECTS

10000 Days

github.com/cesarsiguencia/10000-days | cs-10000-days-33ee2045b3a6.herokuapp.com

- An application for invited guests to register and interact with one another for a one of a kind upcoming social gathering.
- Role: Sole developer | Tools: Handlebars, Sequelize, MySQL, Node, Express, JavaScript, MVC model

Technify In Python

github.com/cesarsiguencia/technify-in-python | technify-in-python-cce9848f5fbf.herokuapp.com

- An intuitive social media app for developers to communicate and share worthy technology related links.
- Role: Sole developer | Tools: Python, Flask, PyMySQL, SQLAlchemy, Bcrypt, JavaScript

Dine N' Wine

github.com/cesarsiguencia/dine-n-wine | cesarsiguencia.github.io/dine-n-wine

- An international recipe site for users to search for instructions, ingredients, nutrition facts, and save favorites
- Role: Group front end developer | Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, APIs,

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mount Carmel-Holy Rosary School, New York, NY

Operations Coordinator

October 2021 - July 2023

Manage student tuition collection system, financial aid, school metrics, and data alignment. Reconciliation of deposits and donations from multiple parties. Manage inventory of school technology and technical support. Ensures impeccable customer service is provided by all office staff to visitors and parents. Lead and prepare various student recruitment events, showcases, and faculty events. Planning of school operation logistics, schedules, field trips, and sanitation maintenance.

Key Accomplishments

- Promoted to this position by school principal in the 21-22 academic year.
- Continue to fulfill all tasks from the previously held Operations Associate position.

Operations Associate November 2018 - October 2021

Communicated with families regarding student incidents, payment deadline reminders, and missing documents. Analyzed and collected general student data, school metrics, and employee payroll daily. Chaperoned 50 students from three classes daily for lunch and recess sessions. Aided the Director of Operations with Article 43 compliance, finances management, inventory, and onboarding employees. Aided the admissions team with collecting inquiries, applications, student registrations, and led tours. *Key Accomplishments*

- Promoted to serve as the school's newsletter author and designer which would be sent to the school community weekly.
- Created and promoted a recycling program in the school for all community members to adhere and follow.

EDUCATION

Columbia University, New York, NY

Certificate: Coding Boot Camp / Full Stack Web Development

August 2014 - May 2018

December 2021 - May 2022

Bowdoin College, Brunswick, ME

Bachelor of Arts: Majors - Sociology and Music / Minor - Mandarin Chinese

- First generation college graduate with 39 completed credits out of a required 32.
- Recipient of the Goldsmith Adams Research Award in 2016 for a summer study abroad in Beijing, China.
- Awarded all expenses paid service trip to volunteer at various San Francisco non-profits during one spring break.